<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regolith 1.5 – Policy and Process</title>
    <link>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Policy and Process on Regolith 1.5</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Privacy</title>
      <link>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/privacy/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;There is nothing in Regolith Linux itself that collects any user data, either anonymously or otherwise. Because Regolith is a customization of Ubuntu Linux, any data collection that Ubuntu is doing will also be performed by Regolith Linux. This website has vanilla Google Analytics integration.  Anonymity is a feature.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Updates</title>
      <link>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/updates/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration-files&#34;&gt;Configuration Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regolith Linux is continually being updated with bug fixes and feature enhancements.  Regolith&#39;s default configuration files live in &lt;code&gt;/etc/regolith/&lt;/code&gt;.  To customize these files, &lt;a href=&#34;https://regolith-linux.org/docs/howto/stage-configs/&#34;&gt;make copies in your user directory&lt;/a&gt; and make changes there.  These copied files in the user directory are owned by the user and will not be modified by Regolith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;package-updates&#34;&gt;Package Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notification of upcoming updates including those that may introduce breaking changes will be announced on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freelists.org/list/regolith-linux&#34;&gt;Regolith Linux Announcements mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a package has been published to the &lt;code&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; PPA, Ubuntu&#39;s built-in package update facility will find the update and either directly apply it or ask the user if they wish to do so, depending on configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;package-promotion&#34;&gt;Package Promotion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development of Regolith happens via updates to source code kept in git repos within the GitHub Regolith Organization.  When a given feature or fix is ready for testing, it is published to the &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt; PPA.  After the change has been verified to work and not cause other problems, it is promoted to the &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; PPA.  Changes being preceived as high-risk will spend some additional time in &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt;.  If a change is a feature, it will stay in &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; until the next version release, but if the change is a bug fix, it will be promoted to the &lt;code&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; PPA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;package-versions&#34;&gt;Package Versions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For packages specific to Regolith, &lt;a href=&#34;https://semver.org/&#34;&gt;symver&lt;/a&gt; will be used.  From Regolith 1.4.1 forward, symver will also be used to describe release versions.  So, if a new release of Regolith will introduce some new component or configuration that is incompatible with the previous version, the major version will be bumped.  Feature releases that do not introduce obvious breaking changes will be minor bumps, and bug fixes will cause a patch bump.
s&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Contribute</title>
      <link>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/contributions/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;As an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/regolith-linux&#34;&gt;open source project&lt;/a&gt;, Regolith is open to anyone to extend, fork, or modify as they see fit.  Additionally, we welcome people to join as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/regolith-linux/people&#34;&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt; to the project. If you already have something in mind, please file an issue describing the change you&#39;re planning to make to Regolith, or discuss in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://regolith-linux.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;Slack channel&lt;/a&gt;.  This ensures work isn&#39;t duplicated or effort wasted.  If you&#39;re interested in seeing what work is available to start with, take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-desktop/labels/help%20wanted&#34;&gt;list of issues looking for help&lt;/a&gt; to see what is needed.  To get a picture of the future, check &lt;a href=&#34;https://regolith-linux.org/news.html#roadmap&#34;&gt;the roadmap&lt;/a&gt;. Regolith is a young project with much potential for improvement!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;financial-support&#34;&gt;Financial Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the 1.3 release, Regolith has joined &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/&#34;&gt;Open Collective&lt;/a&gt; as a way of receiving financial contributions from users. Financial contributions are vital to pay for infrastructure costs and fund future development of both Regolith itself as well as the upstream components that Regolith is composed of.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/regolith/donate&#34;&gt;Go here to contribute to Regolith&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;join-our-slack-channel&#34;&gt;Join our Slack channel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&#34;https://regolith-linux.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to join our Slack channel, which allows you to communicate with the developers of Regolith and other users. Here is where we brainstorm about new features, ways to improve current features, and fix bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing-fixes-and-features&#34;&gt;Testing Fixes and Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When bugs are reported by users, we try to have them verify the fix before enabling the update for everyone. Switching to the &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt; PPA is necessary for Ubuntu to see that a new version of a package is available for testing a new fix or feature.  Once the update has been verified to resolve the problem and not cause any other bugs, it is promoted to the &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; PPA for general consumption by Regolith users.  See &lt;a href=&#34;../updates#package-promotion&#34;&gt;this section&lt;/a&gt; for more details on package promotion, and see &lt;a href=&#34;https://regolith-linux.org/docs/howto/change-ppa/&#34;&gt;this section&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to switch between PPAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;switching-between-ppas&#34;&gt;Switching between PPAs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When bugs are reported by users, we try to have them verify the fix before enabling the update for everyone. Switching to the &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt; PPA is necessary for testing a new fix or feature before it becomes available to the general population via an automatic update.  See this section for more details on package promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;official-regolith-contributors&#34;&gt;Official Regolith Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those that have shown aptitude and desire to help others, fix bugs, or add features to Regolith may be invited to become an official contributor.  Official contributors have more abilities with Regolith source repos and have a high level of trust and agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tasks&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regolith is a volunteer effort, and so there are no specific expectations regarding how much or in what way people contribute. However here are some tasks that are of great help to the project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groom GitHub issues.  If an issue is pending a response from a user and there is no response from the issue creator, close it.  If an issue has been resolved but not closed, also close it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To learn about and contribute to the future roadmap, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/regolith-linux/projects&#34;&gt;see here&lt;/a&gt; for project planning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a young project, there are a lot of rough edges so if you want to work in fixes that&#39;s great but also if you&#39;re interested in new features that&#39;s fine too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help with release planning.  We try for a release every 3 - 4 months.  Besides feature development and bug fixes, documentation and testing are needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For new features, it is recommended to create a &amp;ldquo;request for comment&amp;rdquo; issue (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-i3-gaps-config/issues/6&#34;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;) and allow some time for user feedback.  These RfCs will be advertised via the mailing list and official Twitter account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Support</title>
      <link>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/support/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Regolith Linux is an open source project created and maintained by volunteers.  At this time there is no method for getting paid support.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-desktop/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub issues&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://regolith-linux.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;Slack channel&lt;/a&gt; are recommended ways of finding fixes or asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Development</title>
      <link>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://regolith-linux.org/docs/policy-and-process/development/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;tasks&#34;&gt;Tasks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;triage-bugs-feature-requests&#34;&gt;Triage Bugs, Feature Requests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This task is essentially adding a first layer of organization from inputs from users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notice of bugs and feature requests come as email/slack notifications when the bugs are created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review each incoming gh issue within two days, determine if there is an easy fix.  (best effort)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For issues without an easy fix, add relevant tags, provide some suggestions, give some time for community members to respond with suggestions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For issues that result in a code change (feature/bug fix), make reference to GH URL for issue in commit so that GH will link to it from isssue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix/Feature first goes to &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt; (see steps below that describe this process).  When feature ready, add note to original github issue stating that feature/fix is ready for testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If no response or no issue reported after a few weeks, change is eligible for promotion to &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-user-contributed-pr&#34;&gt;Take user-contributed PR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We accept user contributions with the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get notified of PR from email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify if code change results in general utility for most users, or is more of a personal concern.  If the latter, inform the user politely as such and that the PR will not be merged.  Also consider the complexity and volatility of the change.  Does the change make maintaining Regolith more difficult (things like version specific changes, changes that require Ubuntu-only packages or behavior, changes that are difficult to test, features that rely on specific hw configurations, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assuming PR passes these tests, do a PR review.  Iterate until the changes is ready for inclusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge the change, publish package to &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt; (see below), inform user in PR that package is available for testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publish-package-version-to-unstable&#34;&gt;Publish Package Version to &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This task describes how code sitting on a computer makes it into a package that can be distributed to other users via the package manager facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull commits locally if from others, or whatever local commits if from me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gbp dch&lt;/code&gt; to update changelog with git commits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;/debian/changelog&lt;/code&gt; with correct version and Ubuntu Release (See Rule 1 below).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gbp buildpackage&lt;/code&gt; to locally test package build.  Address all lintian errors and warnings.  Some warnings cannot be fixed, or at least I don&#39;t yet understand how to fix them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If during package build testing, changes are required, add them to existing commit (&lt;code&gt;git commit --amend&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once package build is ready, push package changes to GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to local clone of &lt;code&gt;regolith-builder&lt;/code&gt; repo, run &lt;code&gt;build.sh&lt;/code&gt; script to generate source package and upload to launchpad (this step utilizes Launchpad PKI and as of 7/2/2020 only kgilmer has access to publish packages to Regolith PPAs).  Example invocation: &lt;code&gt;./build.sh package-model-R1.4.2.json ppa:regolith-linux/ubuntu/unstable /tmp/bb56 regolith-compositor-compton-glx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once package is uploaded, monitor email for build error notifications.  Iterate on package dev if errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once package has built in &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt;, sync package versions (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;synchronize-package-versions-across-ubuntu-releases&#34;&gt;Synchronize Package Versions Across Ubuntu Releases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a package is submitted to laundpad.net to be built into a PPA, the package is only built for the Ubuntu version (Bionic, Focal, etc.) that is listed in the package&#39;s changelog file.  Here is an example changelog (&lt;code&gt;debian/changelog&lt;/code&gt;) snippet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;regolith-system (1.4.0.4-1) focal; urgency=medium

  [ Ken Gilmer ]
  * Add gbp conf file, cleanup.

 -- Regolith Linux &amp;lt;regolith.linux@gmail.com&amp;gt;  Sat, 06 Jun 2020 12:39:39 -0700
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here you can see &lt;code&gt;focal&lt;/code&gt; is listed after the package version.  This means that when this package source was uploaded via &lt;code&gt;dput&lt;/code&gt;, launchpad.net built it for the focal release.  Users running other versions of Ubuntu will not see this as an update for their system.  Because Regolith often supports 2 or 3 different releases, Launchpad needs to be instructed to build the packages for our other supported Ubuntu versions as well.  For packages that differ based on Ubuntu version (such as &lt;code&gt;regolith-desktop&lt;/code&gt;) typically there is a seperate branch with a unique changelog entry for each Ubuntu target.  However for almost all other packages, each is able to run as-is on all supported Ubuntu versions, so we do not need to maintain anything per version, but we do have to copy the package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this we simply copy the package from the &lt;em&gt;source&lt;/em&gt; Ubuntu version to the &lt;em&gt;target&lt;/em&gt; Ubuntu version within the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; PPA.  This task is error prone and tedious, because the time it takes for launchpad.net to build a package greatly varies depending on load and other factors.  A package cannot be copied until it&#39;s completely finished building.  Attempting to do so will result in an error. Additionally, packages can only be copied from older Ubuntu versions to newer versions.  So, we must first build a package for the earliest supported version, and then copy it in order to each later version.  All the while keeping the timing constraints in mind so we do not perform an operation on a package that hasn&#39;t completed building (copying is also considered building in launchpad.net).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be possible to write a program that can monitor the state of all packages within a PPA and attempt to copy packages to keep versions consistent, but this program has yet to be written. The current process is to run a script that performs the copies from older to newer versions and simply sleeps between operations hoping to get lucky with the package build times.  This makes it slow and error prone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the package recently published to a PPA, verify that the package has completed building, and that it is on the oldest possible version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the &lt;code&gt;regolith-builder&lt;/code&gt; repo, run the &lt;code&gt;sync-pkg-version.sh&lt;/code&gt; script, and specify the package name.  The following example will copy the package &lt;code&gt;regolith-compoisitor-compton-glx&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;bionic&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;eoan&lt;/code&gt;, and then &lt;code&gt;focal&lt;/code&gt; (note this will change in the future with Ubuntu versions) in the &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt; PPA:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;$ ./sync-pkg-version.sh unstable regolith-compositor-compton-glx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s configured to pause 20 minutes between copies, so will take some time to complete.  When it&#39;s done, check the PPA page (&lt;a href=&#34;https://launchpad.net/~regolith-linux/+archive/ubuntu/unstable&#34;&gt;unstable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://launchpad.net/~regolith-linux/+archive/ubuntu/stable&#34;&gt;stable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://launchpad.net/~regolith-linux/+archive/ubuntu/release&#34;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt;) to determine if the copies were successful.  If not, run the script again until all supported Ubuntu versions have the same version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;promote-packages-from-unstable-to-stable&#34;&gt;Promote Packages from &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a package has been tested in &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt; by the developer of the change (and possibly others), it can be promoted to &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; (and eventually &lt;code&gt;release&lt;/code&gt;, but this requires planning and coordination).  The &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; PPA is intended to provide &amp;ldquo;beta&amp;rdquo; level quality of package updates for those that are willing to add some risk in exchange for earlier fixes and features.  Most users are expected to use &lt;code&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; and so the pool of users should be relatively small.  This gives more time for testing and a smaller risk when issues are discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Package promotion is essentially just copying packages, as we did in the task above to sync a package&#39;s versions across Ubuntu versions.  The difference is that instead of copying between Ubuntu versions, we are first copying from source PPA to target PPA (same Ubuntu version), and then across Ubuntu versions within the target PPA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a script in &lt;code&gt;regolith-builder&lt;/code&gt; specific to this task.  It essentially works as the package sync script, it&#39;s just implementing the copies as described above.  Example that promotes &lt;code&gt;regolith-system&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;$ ./promote-stage.sh unstable stable regolith-system 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that this script has the same limitations and fragility of the sync versions script.  Timing copy operations can fail and so it&#39;s necessary to verify each time that the promotion worked as expected.  If the package was copied successfully to the target PPA but subsequent sync operations failed, then run the &lt;code&gt;sync-pkg-version.sh&lt;/code&gt; script to clean up the package versions in the target PPA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plan-a-subsequent-regolith-release&#34;&gt;Plan a Subsequent Regolith Release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping it simple, we rely on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/regolith-linux/projects&#34;&gt;GitHub project planning feature&lt;/a&gt; available in the Regolith organization.  Workflow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new project to house and manage issues related to the release.  Generally 3 columns seems to work well (not done, in process, complete).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go through the GitHub issues and determine which issues have or should be fixed in the project created in the above step.  For those issues, specify the project in the drop-down to the right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As issues are created, continue to add them to the new project as-needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any features that are expected to be in the release, and do not already have issues, need to have issues created so they can be tracked in the project.  Ideally, the project should define all changes that were made from the previous version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As bugs get fixed and features get implemented, use the project facility to synchronize the issue status with the project status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the scope is finalized for the release and all associated issues are in the &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; column, the project is complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the project link to communicate with users and other contributors the status of the release or an issue associated with the release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once a project is complete (has been shipped, no critical bugs), the project can be marked as complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-a-snapshot-of-regolith-for-a-release&#34;&gt;Test a Snapshot of Regolith for a Release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; PPA is a staging area for the next upcoming Regolith release.  Packages should not be copied into the &lt;code&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; PPA unless they are specifically critical bugs.  Features and lesser important bugs should be held in &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; until a release occurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;testing-via-ppa&#34;&gt;Testing via PPA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test the packages in stable, simply add the PPA to your test environment and install Regolith as it would normally be installed (substituting the &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; PPA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;testing-an-iso&#34;&gt;Testing an ISO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;regolith-builder&lt;/code&gt; repo contains the files &lt;code&gt;create-iso.txt&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;package-iso-*&lt;/code&gt; text files that describe the steps necessary to generate a Regolith ISO from a PPA.  Follow these steps with the Cubic ISO builder to generate an ISO.  Boot a test environment with the ISO to perform testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;perform-a-regolith-release&#34;&gt;Perform a Regolith Release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once testing a release in the &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; PPA has been confirmed to be of acceptable quality, perform the following steps to execute the release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate the upcoming update on the &lt;code&gt;release-plan&lt;/code&gt; Slack channel, linking to the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sync all packages from the &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; PPA to the &lt;code&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; PPA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate that users will now be able to update.  Provide release notes or link to project if none available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a new ISO w/ the Cubic tool (described above) and upload this to the &lt;code&gt;regolith-desktop&lt;/code&gt; releases page.  Use consistent entries for the various field when generating the release on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate the update is available on the mailing list and Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor Slack and GitHub issues for any problems users may encounter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-a-new-package-to-regolith&#34;&gt;Add a New Package to Regolith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create the GitHub repo in the Regolith org.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the debian package utilities to generate the package metadata that is stored in the &lt;code&gt;debian&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the debian package utilities to verify that the package builds succesfully locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the steps in task &lt;strong&gt;Publish Package Version to &lt;code&gt;unstable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from step 7 such that the new package is installable by users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;update-package-model&#34;&gt;Update Package Model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build scripts use a JSON file that defines a few things necessary in order to build source packages and upload them to launchpad.net.  These files live in the &lt;code&gt;regolith-builder&lt;/code&gt; repo with the schema &lt;code&gt;package-model-&amp;lt;regolith version&amp;gt;.json&lt;/code&gt;.  Here is an abbreviated snippet of &lt;code&gt;package-model-R1.4.1.txt&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34; data-lang=&#34;json&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;packages&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;gitRepoUrl&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-system.git&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;packageName&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;regolith-system&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;buildPath&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;regolith-system&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;upstreamTarball&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;packageBranch&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;master&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a40000&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a40000&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a40000&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;copies&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;ppaUrl&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~kgilmer/ubuntu/speed-ricer&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;packageName&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;i3-snapshot&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;sourceVersion&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;bionic&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;targetVersions&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#4e9a06&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;eoan&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The file contains two sections, &amp;ldquo;packages&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;copies&amp;rdquo;.  Packages defines how the &lt;code&gt;build.sh&lt;/code&gt; script can go about generating a source package for a given package.  It requires the git repo, the name of the package, the root directory in the repo from which the build should execute, any specific source tarball to use, and the git branch.  The Copies section describes packages that are not built as part of Regolith but copied from other PPAs.  For example many GTK theme and icon packages are already hosted by other developers on launchpad.net and for Regolith, we simply need to copy them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps to add a new package model for a new Regolith version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy from the latest release to the new one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make changes as needed to the new package model to support the new Regolith version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When running the &lt;code&gt;build.sh&lt;/code&gt; script to generate source packages, specify the new package model in the parameter list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rules&#34;&gt;Rules&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;r1---ubuntu-version-in-changelog&#34;&gt;R1 - Ubuntu version in Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packages should be published with changelog entry of oldest supported Ubuntu release (&lt;code&gt;bionic&lt;/code&gt; as of 7/2/2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;r2---git-branch-names-for-ubuntu-versions&#34;&gt;R2 - Git branch names for Ubuntu versions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For packages which must maintain Ubuntu-version-specific differences, a distinct version string must be generated for each version of Ubuntu.  In this case, the package&#39;s git repo will maintain a branch named after the Ubuntu release it builds, with the exception of the branch &lt;code&gt;debian&lt;/code&gt; always tracking the current production release of Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
